vbprofiles.com 2019-04-02

# Privacy

## Spoke Software Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy has been updated to reflect the new features and functionalities of Spoke Software, Inc.'s ("Spoke Software" or "Spoke") products and services as well as all the member sites of Spoke Intelligence. This Privacy Policy sets forth Spoke's policy with respect to information, including personally identifiable data ("Personal Data") that is collected from users of the Spoke Intelligence websites (available at http://www.spoke.com and http://www.vbprofiles.com ) and related Spoke services, including the search engine, informational directory and database services (together with the Spoke websites, the "Spoke Services"). 

Spoke Software believes that privacy is not just a feature or a legal document; it is the philosophy on which we founded the company. Concern for privacy permeates everything we build. This focus enables us to design services that we feel comfortable using and recommending to our own colleagues and family. Spoke is committed to protecting the privacy of both our users and the individuals listed in the Spoke Services. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact Spoke via our support site . 

## Information We Collect and Use

**Registration Data:** Spoke collects Personal Data from users who register for the Spoke Services (for example, username, name, company, phone number and email address), use certain parts of the Spoke Services, contact us with inquiries or respond to one of our surveys. Spoke uses this information to establish and deliver Spoke Services to the individual. Spoke may use this information to contact registered users to notify them of product and service updates, provide instruction, and to deliver other service related information. Spoke may also contact registered users to request additional information and feedback. In addition, if you consent at the time of signup, Spoke may contact you to inform you of updates or new features. If you wish to be removed from such secondary mailings you may do so by the means provided in such email or as described below. 

Name, title, and company are the primary identifiers used by the Spoke system and may be disclosed by voluntary user action on the Spoke Service, including but not limited to completing a profile, a referral, or an information request. Direct contact information (including email, address, and telephone number) may only be made visible through the Spoke Services by the action and with the permission of the registered user who already possesses such information. For more information on the operation of information requests and referrals, see the Spoke Directory section below. 

Registered users can use the Spoke Services to host relationship information in their Spoke Contacts (similar to an online contact list). Relationship information sent to Spoke servers by the registered user will remain the property - as between Spoke and the registered user - of the registered user. Spoke will not review, share, distribute or reference such data except as may be required to provide the requested Spoke Services, or as provided in the Spoke Terms of Service, or as may be required by law. 

**Anonymous Contributors:** Spoke collects certain information from users who contribute to but do not register for the Spoke Services. Examples of this may be a user who anonymously edits entries listed in Spoke's online directory, or a user who browses the Spoke website but does not sign up for an account. For users who anonymously contribute to the Spoke Services, Spoke collects certain technical information related to that user including IP addresses, the page the user was referred from, and the time that the contributions were made. 

**Non-Identifiable or Aggregated Data:** For all users, Spoke may automatically collect and analyze information regarding the use of the Spoke Services and activity on the Spoke website. Information collected may include but is not limited to web site traffic volume, IP addresses, referral sources, frequency of visits, type and time of transactions, type of browser and operating system, etc. This information is logged to help diagnose technical problems, identify abusive behavior, administer the site, and improve the quality and types of service delivered. Spoke may also collect, track and analyze information that does not personally identify a user in aggregate form. This aggregate data will be used at Spoke's discretion and may be shared with third parties, but with no personally identifiable information attached. 

**Third Parties:** Spoke will not disclose registration information to third parties, including, but not limited to, companies affiliated with Spoke, without the registered user's consent or as otherwise stated in this privacy policy. 

  * If at some point Spoke sells all or a portion of its assets or business, customer information is an asset that may be transferred or acquired by a third party. The third party would then have the right to continue using the transferred information (including Personal Data) as set forth in this policy.
  * Spoke may release or exchange Personal Data if required to do so to comply with applicable law, or to enforce its rights or agreements, or to prevent fraud or harm to Spoke's business, property, rights or interests.
  * Spoke may also employ companies and people to perform tasks on its behalf (such as for servicing registered user accounts), and may need to share Personal Data with these agents to establish and deliver service to registered users. Spoke's agents do not receive any right to use Personal Data about registered users beyond what is necessary to perform these tasks.
  * We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name, and we obtain the customer's consent prior to doing so.

Spoke offers online profiles of companies and people on Spoke Intelligence (http://www.spoke.com, and http://www.vbprofiles.com ) Profiles ("Spoke Profiles"). Spoke Profiles may be created and edited by registered and unregistered users. The information that may be included in a Spoke Profile includes but is not limited to pictures, videos, professional overview, professional experience, education, interests and favorite links. 

Contributions to Spoke Profiles made by registered or unregistered users ("User Contributions") are aggregated and made available for public view. User Contributions are aggregated according to the registration status and login status of the user who made the contribution, or according to the relevance to a specific industry or trend. Certain data regarding User Contributions, such as the times that the contributions were made and the number of edits that have been made, are also publicly available via User Contributions lists and in aggregated forms published by other users. All User Contributions (original and edited) are recorded by Spoke as users may wish to look at prior versions of a profile. User Contributions are retained and may be displayed by Spoke even after the user cancels his or her account and suppresses his or her data on the Spoke Profile and Spoke Directory. Even after a Spoke Profile is removed from public view, users responsible for administration and moderation of the Spoke Services may still access the information in order to facilitate opt-outs and site maintenance and compliance. 

The publicly available information contained in Spoke Profiles may be shared with third parties to enable those third parties to publish the information on their own web sites or media platforms. Spoke is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such sites or other information providers. 

## Suppressing Your Information in Spoke Intelligence Profiles

Because Spoke is constantly gathering information from publicly available sources and members, the best way to avoid having your information made visible via Spoke is to request removal or suppression of your information from public data sources (from which Spoke receives that information) and to actively make efforts to keep your personal information confidential whenever you are online. 

Spoke voluntarily offers registered and unregistered individuals the opportunity to suppress their information from display in the Spoke Profiles and Spoke Directory. Suppression means that information will be hidden from display on public areas of the Spoke Profiles and Spoke Directory. Spoke retains some identification information in Spoke's databases after receiving a suppression request for the purpose of maintaining an effective opt-out list to ensure that republication of this information does not occur. 

All users can suppress their information by clicking on the "Suppression" link located on the bottom of any Spoke Profile page. Clicking this link takes you to a contact form where you submit the URL of the profile you wish to suppress and provide an email associated with that profile so that we can confirm the suppression request. Once confirmed, the page will be suppressed. Users may also request suppression of their information by submitting a suppression request directly to Spoke by clicking here. 

## Access and Correction of Registered User Personally Identifiable Information

If a registered user's Personal Data (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address) changes, or if a user no longer desires our Spoke Services, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate registered users' Personal Data the registered user has contributed to the Spoke Services. Please be aware that even after your request for removal from our systems is processed, Spoke Software may for a time retain residual information about you and your relationship information in our backup and/or archival copies of our database (e.g., our records of deletion). Spoke will make reasonable commercial efforts to assure that such information is deleted as soon as possible following your request. 

Registered users may make changes to their Personal Data (generally effective upon submission) or seek a Personal Data Review via the "profile" page in their Spoke dashboard. Registered users may also contact support via a support request. Please see the Suppressing Your Information in the Spoke Directory section above for access and correction rights for unregistered individuals. If after trying these methods, you believe they are not effective, you may also send a letter seeking the necessary changes or deletions to the following address: 

Spoke Software, Inc.   
2930 Domingo Avenue #244   
Berkeley, CA 94705   
Attn: Personal Information Review 

Access requests will be responded to within 30 days of receipt of the request. 

## Opting Out of Spoke Communications

If you no longer wish to receive promotional communications from Spoke, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each promotional communication, or by sending a letter requesting that you not receive specific communications to the following address: 

Spoke Software, Inc.   
2930 Domingo Avenue #244   
Berkeley, CA 94705   
Attn: Opt Out Requests 

Users must be able to receive service-related communications in order to continue accessing the Spoke service. 

## Cookies & Beacons

Spoke Software uses cookies and beacons to assist in delivering the service and to provide a positive and personalized registered user experience. Cookies are files sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Our persistent and session ID cookies are used to identify unique visitors and to provide a personalized user experience. Other than user login and password information (which are stored on your computer if you select the "Login automatically" feature on the login page), we do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. Beacons are bits of code that function similar to cookies. Our beacons are embedded in outgoing emails and generate a call back to the Spoke server when such emails are opened. Spoke uses beacons to track the status of sent emails. 

We may use advertising network providers to help present, better target, and measure the effectiveness of, advertisements on Spoke's sites. The use of session ID cookies by our partners and/or advertising network providers to do so is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. 

## Security

Spoke Software has implemented processes designed to protect user information and maintain security. Each registered user is assigned a unique user name and password which is required to access their account and relationship information. It is the user's responsibility to protect the security of his or her login information. Spoke's servers are located in secure server environments. Firewalls and other advanced security technologies are employed to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. These safeguards help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of data. 

## Third Party Sites

Spoke's sites may contain links to third party web sites not associated with or controlled by Spoke, or to other sources of information about companies or individuals. Spoke Software is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such sites or other information providers. Users will need to review the policy statements of these sites or information providers to understand their privacy policies. 

## Integrating Third Party Services within Spoke

One of the special features of the Spoke Service is that it allows you to enable various online third party services, such as social media and networking services, ("Third Party Services") to be directly integrated into your Spoke experience. By directly integrating these services, Spoke is able to make your online experiences richer, and more personalized. If you choose to take advantage of this feature, you will need to provide Spoke with your user name and password for the relevant Third Party Services to enable integration. By enabling such Third Party Services, you are authorizing Spoke to pass your login information to these service providers for this purpose. When you add a Third Party Service account to the Spoke Service, Spoke will collect your login information and other relevant information necessary to enable the Spoke Service to access that Third Party Service and your data contained within that Third Party Service. However, please remember that the manner in which Third Party Services use, store and disclose your information is governed solely by the policies of such third parties, and Spoke shall have no liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of any Third Party Service that may be enabled within the Spoke Services. 

## Privacy Policy Changes

Spoke Software reserves the right to make changes to this privacy statement. Any material changes to this statement will be prominently posted online and accessible via the Spoke user portal 30 days prior to taking effect. 

_Last Updated December 2nd, 2013_
